Inventory of the Charles Campbell Papers 1743-1896
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Family and Professional Papers (Box 2-17)
  - Letters, 1890-1899., 7 items. (Box-folder 16:95-101)
    - K[ittie] J. Henley, Mountainville, Tennessee to Cousin [Mrs. L. M. Robinson, Charles Campbell's daughter[?]], 25 March 1890., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 16:97)
      Moore and Campbell family genealogy notes and inquiries.
    - K[ittie] J. Henley, Mountainville, Tennessee to Cousin [Elizabeth Campbell Mabin [?]], 28 March 1890., 8 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 16:98)
      Henley and Keller family genealogy notes.
    - Kittie J. Henley, Mountainville, Tennessee to Mr. & Mrs. L[eiper] M[oore] Robinson(Charles Campbell's daughter), 20 February 1892., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 16:99)
    - Benj[amin] S. Ewell, James City County, Virginia to Mary Campbell Robinson, 22 February 1892., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 16:100)
      Will add her great grandfather, Alexander Spotswood Moore, to the list of William and Mary alumni.
    - Leiper Moore Robinson's memoir of his service in the Confederate Army, March-April 1896., 47 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 16:101)
  - Letters, n.d., 60 items. (Box-folder 17:1-60)
    - Lucy Ashby to [?] Campbell, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:1)
      Asks for the loan of a book she had seen at Hazel Hill.
    - I. P[age] Aylett, Richmond, [Virginia] to "Cousin", 1 April n.y., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:2)
      Came in the stage; asks her to take a trip.
    - H. V. L. Bird, et al to C[harles] Campbell, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:3)
      Are sorry school is letting out.
    - Marion R. Booth to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 26 July n.y., ALS. 2 pages. (Box-folder 17:4)
      Sends inscription on memorial of John Curtis.
    - R. P. Branch, R. M. College to Charles Campbell, 16 August n.y., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:5)
      Elected to honorary membership in the Franklin Literary Society.
    - Charles Campbell to [T. P. Branch, R. M. College], n.d., 1 page. ACyS. (Box-folder 17:6)
      Accepts his election to the Franklin Literary Society.
    - [Charles Campbell] to Thomas Ritchie, Richmond, n.d. (Box-folder 17:7)
      A letter to the editor of the Enquirer giving Campbell's impressions of a series of county election campaigns.
    - C[harles] C[ampbell] to [?], n.d., 1 page. ACys. (Box-folder 17:8)
      Age of Jamestown Church uncertain.
    - [Charles Campbell] to [?], n.d., 1 page. Incomplete. ACy. (Box-folder 17:9)
      Betty going to Salt Sulphur Springs; Ma and Cally well; Fred Robbins arrived from Texas.
    - Charles Campbell to [?], n.d., 1 page. Incomplete. AcyS. (Box-folder 17:10)
      Asks for facts about family history.
    - [Charles Campbell] to [?], n.d., 2 pages. ADf. (Box-folder 17:11)
      Returns Table of Contents. Copyright must be in Charles Campbell's name or will be contravention of contract. Mr. Lippincott proposed a half interest in the plates, but Charles Campbell had contract altered to be sure copyright solely in his name. If terms infringed on, will be without Charles Campbell's consent. If publishers lose anything, is due to lack of precautions on their side.
    - M[ary] B. Cart[er], Centre Hill to Charles [Campbell], [Petersburg], 19 September n.y., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:12)
      Inviting him to Shirley. Encloses $30.
    - M[ary] B. Carter, Shirley to Mildred W. Campbell, Petersburg, [?] May n.y., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:13)
      Social news; she has been visited by an Englishman. Having sent grease, she awaits soap.
    - [Mary B. Carter], Richmond to Mildred [W. Campbell],[Petersburg], 26 August n.y., 4 pages. AL. (Box-folder 17:14)
      Her son has gone down to Shirley but she has stayed behind. She is ill. Family news.
    - M[ary] B. Carter, Shirley to Mrs. [Mildred W.] Campbell, Petersburg, 30 August n.y., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:15)
      Has sent her two boys to her; asks her to make clothes for them.
    - M[ary] B. C[arter], Shirley to [Mildred W. Campbell], "Monday Morning," n.d., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:16)
      Has just returned from Richmond with a cold. Fears she is growing forgetful. Asks her to deposit $10 in savings bank for her.
    - M[ary] B. C[arter] to Mildred W. Campbell, Petersburg, "Monday Morning," n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:17)
      Encloses some money to be put in savings bank. Hopes to send her some peaches.
    - M[ary] B. C[arter], Richmond to [Mildred W.] Campbell, Petersburg, "Tuesday," n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:18)
      Family news. Encloses $10.
    - M[ary] B. Carter, Wendson to [Mildred W. Campbell], "Tuesday Morning," n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:19)
      She is enjoying her rest away from home. Her son, Robert, once near death, has apparently recovered.
    - M[ary] B. C[arter] to [Mildred W. Campbell], "Tuesday Night," n.d., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:20)
      Social news. She has been very sick, but daughter Landonia is much better. She is pleased with her new son.
    - M[ary] B. C[arter] to Mildred [W. Campbell],"Wednesday Morn," n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:21)
      Family news. Cousin Leigh Wickham there until Friday.
    - M[ary] B. C[arter] to Mildred [W.] Campbell, Petersburg, "Wednesday," n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:22)
      Sorry to hear she cannot come. Also regrets being unable to send any butter or lard.
    - M[ary] B. C[arter] to Mildred [W. Campbell],"Thursday Morning," n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:23)
      Family news. She has not been well, but feels better now.
    - M[ary] B. C[arter] to [Mildred W. Campbell], "Thursday Morn," n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:24)
      She leaves Saturday for Hickory Hill. Hopes to see her today.
    - M[ary] B. C[arter], Shirley to [Mildred W. Campbell], "Friday Morning," n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:25)
      Mrs. Kay, a neighbor, is very ill and dying and wishes to see her children before she dies. Asks her to send the children to Shirley tomorrow; encloses $1 for train fare.
    - M[ary] B. C[arter] to Mildred W. Campbell, n.d. (Box-folder 17:26)
      Have sent beef and a turkey; hope they will come down at Easter.
    - M. B. Carter to M[ildred] W. Campbell, Petersburg, n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:27)
      Norain; hopes Mr. Nelson hasn't failed; urges them to come for a visit.
    - M[ary] C[arter] to Mrs. [Mildred W.] Campbell, Petersburg, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:28)
      Asks her to send some cotton. Asks Alexander [S. Campbell] to come for a visit.
    - M[ary] B. C[arter] to [Mildred W. Campbell], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:29)
      Asks her to come for a visit. She is planning a fair in order to raise money to build a home for their preacher.
    - M[ary B.] C[arter] to M[ildred] W. Campbell, Petersburg, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:30)
      Asks her to buy $2.00 worth of leeches for her when she returns from Richmond.
    - M[ary] B. C[arter] to Mildred [W. Campbell],n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:31)
      Encloses a letter with news of her father. Hopes her son Charlie can find work in Petersburg.
    - M[ary] B. Carter to [Mildred W.] Campbell, Petersburg, n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:32)
      Asks her to buy some cotton and some buttons for her. Sends some butter. Asks her to come and bring Alexander S. Campbell, and inquires for news of Charles Campbell.
    - M[ary] B. C[arter] to [Mildred W.] Campbell, Petersburg, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:33)
      Her sons are going up to see her. Encloses $2.50; asks her to buy a shawl. Also encloses $10 to put in savings bank in the name of Co[a]t[e]sworth Pinckney Mason.
    - M[ary] B. C[arter] to [Mildred W.] Campbell, Petersburg, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:34)
      Encloses $10.
    - M[ary] B. C[arter] to Mildred [W. Campbell],n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:35)
      Hopes to visit Dr. Eppes next week.
    - M[ary] B. C[arter] to [Mildred W. Campbell], [Richmond], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:36)
      Acknowledges receipt of the money she sent. Invites her to spend Christmas with her if John and Betty (Campbell) Maben have left by then. Expects visit from her brother Robert soon.
    - M[ary] B. Carter to M[ildred] W. Campbell, Petersburg, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:37)
      Encloses "sad news" for Martha and Sarah Kay. Family news.
    - Doctor Craik accepts Col. Bland's invitation to dinner, n.d., 1 page. AL. (Box-folder 17:38)
    - R. B. Gooch, Washington to C[harles] Campbell, Petersburg, 3 June n.y., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:39)
      Can't make permanent plans, as will cross the Atlantic soon. Not sure of going to Richmond next Winter; could do well in Washington. If go to Richmond, will begin publishing the Debates twice a week. Does Charles Campbell have left over type from his paper? If so, will have it printed in Petersburg.
    - Arch Good[?] to [?], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:40)
      Letter concerns a dispute over land.
    - L. D. H., Charlotte C[ourt] H[ouse] to [Charles] Campbell, 26 December n.y., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:41)
      Would like to board at Charles Campbell's while teaching school.
    - Anna F. Lex to Anna [Burdsall ?],n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:42)
      Poetry; hopes she will return to Philadelphia.
    - Diagnosis of a thyroid condition, by Dr. J. H. McGuire, n.d. (Box-folder 17:43)
    - E[lizabeth] M. Maben, Richmond to Anna [Campbell], Petersburg, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:44)
      Sorry to hear Charles has given up his school.
    - E[lizabeth] M. Maben, Richmond to [Charles Campbell], 25 April n.y., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:45)
      Sorry to hear of death of his daughter, Fannie. Consoles him.
    - E[lizabeth] M. Maben, Richmond to Mrs. M[ildred] W. Campbell, Petersburg, 19 July n.y., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:46)
      Invites her to Richmond during her illness. Indecision about their vacation trip. Conveys news received from Aleck.
    - Rob[er]t W. Meade to C[harles] Campbell, Petersburg, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:47)
      Sends a manuscript. Thanks him for sending "Lamb's delightful book." Will return copy of Southern Literary Messenger when he is in Petersburg on Sunday.
    - Nath Nelson to Charles Campbell, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:48)
      Sends a sample of the tuckahoe root.
    - Cha[rle]s H. Phelps to [Charles] Campbell, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:49)
      Says goodbye.
    - R. J. Poulson to Charles Campbell, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:50)
      Suggests he can obtain interesting records from "our clerk's office," records commence 1663 and detail social life.
    - Maria H. Raye to Mrs. Campbell, 9 February n.y., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:51)
      Thank you note; has been confined to the house; hopes Mrs. Campbell will recover from the effects of her fall; would like to see Mary and Nanny.
    - A. B. Van Zandt, Hudson [?] to [Charles] Campbell, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:52)
      He has been quite sick. If he cannot come down next week, he will send his lists.
    - Evelyn B. Walker to Charles Campbell, n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 17:53)
      Sends $15 tuition.
    - T[homas] H. Wynne, Richmond to C[harles] Campbell, n.d., 2 pages. Date torn. ALS. (Box-folder 17:54)
      Laments that subscriptions for selling books is necessary, but offers to help.
    - [?], Washington, D.C. to [?], editor of the Petersburg Statesman, 6 August n.y., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 17:55)
    - [?] to [Editor of the Southern Literary Messenger], n.d., 1 page. AL. (Box-folder 17:56)
      Points out some errors in last edition of the Messenger. Informs him of the publication of a new historical magazine in Boston, and of the impending publication of other historical items.
    - [?] to [?], n.d., 4 pages. AL. (Box-folder 17:57)
      Remembers childhood.
    - [?] to [?], n.d., 2 pages. AL. (Box-folder 17:58)
      Apologizes for not seeing him.
    - Letter concerns a dispute over land, n.d., 2 pages. AL. (Box-folder 17:59)
    - Description of a garden, n.d., 5 pages. ACy. (Box-folder 17:60)
  Series 3: Manuscript Volumes
- Manuscript Volumes of Charles Campbell and his wife, Anna, 1750-1871. (Box 18-27)
  - Diary of Charles Campbell, 1861 June 30-July 20., MsV. 1 (Box-folder 18:1)
  - Diary of Charles Campbell, 1861 July 20-August 9., MsV. 2 (Box-folder 18:2)
  - Diary of Charles Campbell, 1861 August 10-October 3., MsV. 3 (Box-folder 18:3)
  - Diary of Charles Campbell, 1861 October 4-1862 April 5., MsV. 4 (Box-folder 18:4)
    Written in "Catalogue of the Library of Petersburg, Virginia" (1854).
  - Diary of Charles Campbell, 1862 June 15-July 14., MsV. 5 (Box-folder 18:5)
  - Various Journals, Diaries and an Index, 1861-1864., MsV. 6 (Box-folder 18:6)
    Minutes of the Ladies Club of Washington Street Church, Petersburg, for soldiers relief, 1861 July 1-July 27
    "Diary of the War", 1863 June 28-1864 July 22
    Charles Campbell: Journal, 1861 April 22-May 4
    Journal, 1862 July 16-August 3
    Index to diaries by date #1-9.
  - Journal of Anna Burdsall, 1840 October-1841 May., MsV. 7 (Box-folder 19:7)
  - Notes on books and lectures; diary of Anna Burdsall, 1841 November 11-December 4., MsV. 8 (Box-folder 19:8)
  - Diary of Anna Burdsall Campbell, 1841-1854., MsV. 9 (Box-folder 19:9)
    Dates include 1841 December-1842 June 8; 1844 May 6-September 12; 1849 August 8; 1850 April 27; 1850 October 15; 1854 March 18.
  - Diary of Anna Campbell, which also includes occasional notes by Charles Campbell, 1850-1870., MsV. 10 (Box-folder 19:10)
  - Scrapbook of Anna Campbell; newspaper clippings, n.d., MsV. 11 (Box-folder 19:11)
  - Letters C., and newspaper clippings, 1750-1790., MsV. 12 (Box-folder 20:12)
  - Bound volume, 1861-1868., MsV. 13 (Box-folder 20:13)
    Charles Campbell's account book for Anderson Seminary, 1861-1862; inventory of Anderson Seminary, 1868.
  - Accounts and Clippings, 1848-1863., MsV. 14 (Box-folder 20:14)
    Charles Campbell's estimate of family expenses, 1863 July 20; clippings on Petersburg; household accounts 1848-1863 (partially covered by clippings pasted in).
  - Inventories and accounts, 1848-1867., MsV. 15 (Box-folder 20:15)
    Inventory of Rahway house contents, 1848-1851; cash receipts and disbursements ledger, 1863-1867; accounts for Anderson Seminary shoe purchases, 1863; extracts from letters; Burdsall & Co. accounts, 1848.
  - Charles Campbell's Gould's Universal Index, n.d., MsV. 16 (Box-folder 21:16)
    Has Charles Campbell's notes on a variety of subjects.
  - Charles Campbell's volume #14, n.d., MsV. 17 (Box-folder 21:17)
    History of British in Virginia 1781; life of Lavinia Maria More, pages. 31-69; discussion of immigrants.
  - Charles Campbell's volume #9, 1826, n.d., MsV. 18 (Box-folder 21:18)
    Poem: "Edwin"; notes on Bacon's Rebellion; notes on railroad engineering: Journal, 1826; lists of authors; life of Isaac Jefferson, Anecdotica Revolutionana; roll of Tuscumbia School and Sommerville School.
  - Bound volume, n.d., MsV. 19 (Box-folder 21:19)
    List of books Charles Campbell has read; list of magazines and reviews received; memoir of his courtship and marriage to Elvira Callaway (24 pages.); notes for History of Virginia; list of manuscripts Charles Campbell has collected.
  - Charles Campbell's volume #10, 1838, n.d., MsV. 20 (Box-folder 22:20)
    Essays on various topics; historical notes; list of family portraits at Shirley by room, with sketch of each person, 1838; list of manuscripts published in various magazines. 1838 October 21.
  - Charles Campbell's volume #12, 1839, n.d., MsV. 21 (Box-folder 22:21)
    Charles Campbell's notes on Walter Raleigh; Clayton of Gloucester county; genealogical notes, Lee family; epitaph of Thomas Ludwell, Bruton Parish; misc. tombstone inscriptions; DD's journal, 1839 December 7, pages 57-63; list of 32 pieces published on Virginia, pages 64-65; list of plantation on James River, pages 69-71; lists opinions of his Lyceum speech, pages 96-98; distribution of "Bland Papers", pages 120-121; Lord's Prayer in Mohawk, 1839 October, page 42.
  - Description of Shirley by Charles Campbell., 5 pages. MsV. 22 (Box-folder 22:22)
  - Historical notes by Charles Campbell; newspaper clippings., MsV. 23 (Box-folder 22:23)
  - Historical notes by Charles Campbell; newspaper clippings., MsV. 24 (Box-folder 22:24)
  - Charles Campbell's volume #7., MsV. 25 (Box-folder 22:25)
    List of memoirs published; Charles Campbell journal; historical notes.
  - [Charles Campbell?] journal, 1839 December 11-December 26., MsV. 26 (Box-folder 22:26)
  - Journal and other notes of [Charles Campbell?], 1846 June 3., MsV. 27 (Box-folder 22:27)
  - Charles Campbell's notes on various subjects; journal, 1857 April 12-1859., MsV. 28 (Box-folder 22:28)
  - Journal of Charles Campbell describes a trip to Warrenton and brother's farm and describes the events during his visit, 1849 July 9., Incomplete. MsV. 29 (Box-folder 22:29)
  - Notebook containing notes on furniture and books for the Petersburg Library, [1853]., MsV. 30 (Box-folder 22:30)
  - Charles Campbell's book of exercises for his pupils., MsV. 31 (Box-folder 23:31)
  - Charles Campbell's bound volume #3, 1841-1856., MsV. 32 (Box-folder 23:32)
    Heads of questions for Debating Society.
  - Exercises for school children [Charles Campbell's]., 43 pages. MsV. 33 (Box-folder 23:33)
  - Bound volume #4., MsV. 34 (Box-folder 23:34)
    Newspaper clippings pasted over Charles Campbell's notes from law school.
  - Newspaper clippings on Civil War., MsV. 35 (Box-folder 23:35)
  - Bound volume, 14 December 1847., MsV. 36 (Box-folder 24:36)
    Civil War newspaper clippings pasted in a book entitled Homers Book VI, Volume II, Miss Lucie Nelson, Petersburg, Virginia.
  - Charles Campbell's bound volume #6., MsV. 37 (Box-folder 24:37)
    Newspaper clippings pasted over John Campbell's account book.
  - Charles Campbell's newspaper clippings pasted over John W. Campbell's 1837 ledger., MsV. 38 (Box-folder 24:38)
  - Charles Campbell's volume #15, 1831-1832., MsV. 39 (Box-folder 25:39)
    Newspaper clippings pasted over John W. Campbell's cash book.
  - John W. Campbell's day book #2; partially covered by newspaper clippings, 1818-1819., MsV. 40 (Box-folder 25:40)
  - Newspaper clippings; pressed plants; article on Bland Papers; article by Charles Campbell on Guilford Dudley in the Revolution; "The Contest," a pamphlet [18th century]., MsV. 41 (Box-folder 25:41)
  - Charles Campbell's scrapbook: newspaper clippings; signatures clipped from letters; signatures cut from letters; list of articles by Charles Campbell; index to clippings in book, 1849, n.d., MsV. 42 (Box-folder 25:42)
  - Newspaper clippings, ca. 1840-1860., MsV. 43 (Box-folder 26:43)
  - Charles Campbell's volume #2., MsV. 44 (Box-folder 26:44)
    Newspaper clippings.
  - Almanac, 1871., MsV. 45 (Box-folder 26:45)
    Manuscript notes on farming included.
  Series 4: Miscellaneous Material
- Miscellaneous Material, 1712-1868. (Box 27-28)
  - John Tyler autograph. (Box-folder 27:1)
  - List of addresses., 1 page. Ms. (Box-folder 27:2)
  - List of names, 1770-1800., Ms. (Box-folder 27:3)
  - Biographical information on Charles Campbell., Ms. (Box-folder 27:4)
  - Photograph of Charles Campbell. (Box-folder 27:4a)
  - List of articles by Charles Campbell in various journals., Ms. (Box-folder 27:5)
  - Charles Campbell, Genealogy of the Spotswood Family, 1868., 41 pages. Xerox. (Box-folder 27:6)
  - History of William Clayborne., 3 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 27:7)
  - Extracts from Dandridge family Bible., 2 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 27:8)
  - Various notes on tomatoes; Moore family; trees in Southampton., 2 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 27:9)
  - Copy of epitaph of Sarah Littlepage, 1761., Ms. (Box-folder 27:10)
  - Copy of epitaph of Henry Harrison, 1712-1713., Ms. (Box-folder 27:11)
  - [Charles Campbell?], Shenstone,(Virginia history)., 43 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 27:12)
  - [Charles Campbell?], pages 79-104 of manuscripts; travel description; manuscript on Shakespeare, the Earl of Southampton and 'The Tempest'., Ms. (Box-folder 27:13)
  - Aylette family genealogy., 2 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 27:14)
  - Campbell genealogy., 1 page. Ms. (Box-folder 27:15)
  - Robinson family genealogy., 1 page. Ms. (Box-folder 27:16)
  - Moore family genealogy., 2 page. Ms. (Box-folder 27:17)
  - McCluer family genealogy. (Box-folder 27:18)
  - [Charles Campbell?], biographical material on John Henry., 1 page. Ms. (Box-folder 27:19)
  - Memoir of Patrick Henry; description of the Moore family home, "Chelsea.", 4 page. Ms. (Box-folder 27:20)
  - History of Petersburg; account of the British in Petersburg; newspaper clippings on Petersburg; list of the Petersburg volunteers for 1812. (Box-folder 27:21)
  - Copy of a poem, "Mortally Wounded," by [?], c. 1861-1865., 2 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 28:1)
  - "Dirge," in memory of Ellen Gee by [?]. (Box-folder 28:2)
  - Fragments. (Box-folder 28:3)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings. (Box-folder 28:4)
  - Knitting instructions for "The Sontag.", 2 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 28:5)
  - A poem., 1 page. Ms. (Box-folder 28:6)
  - Fiction., 11 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 28:7)
  - Fiction., 10 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 28:8)
  - A poem., 1 page. Ms. (Box-folder 28:9)
  - Poem, Origin of the Harp. (Box-folder 28:10)
  - Lithograph of John M. Daniel, autographed by him. (Box-folder 28:11)
  Series 5: Addition 1992.33b
- Addition 1992.33b, 1860's. (Othertype 1992.33b)
  Typescript by William Cryer of Charles Campbell diaries, 1860s (in 3 parts).